<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>arch on yuankun@net: ~$</title><link>https://yuankun.me/tags/arch/</link><description>Recent content in arch on yuankun@net: ~$</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 20:50:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuankun.me/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Up a Development Machine</title><link>https://yuankun.me/posts/dev-machine-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 20:50:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuankun.me/posts/dev-machine-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just a few days ago, I completed a &lt;a href="https://yuankun.me/posts/home-server-setup" >home server build&lt;/a>. Today I decided to have a clean OS reinstallation on my development machine due to several reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Firstly, the root partition on this machine is nearing full capacity (thank you, my past self).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Secondly, I&amp;rsquo;m consistently encountering &lt;code>__common_interrupt: 1.55 No irq handler for vector&lt;/code> errors during system bootup. There&amp;rsquo;s a thread in the Arch Forum discussing this issue. Despite my efforts to resolve it through various ombinations of kernel parameters as suggested in the thread, I have not succeeded. It appears that the only viable solution is a BIOS firmware upgrade.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finally, there exists a paradoxical issue: I cannot decrypt the root partition without using my bluetooth keyboard, yet I cannot use my bluetooth keyboard until the root partition is decrypted and mounted (because the bluetooth driver sits in the root partition). This presents a typical chicken and egg problem. My current hack around is to use a wired USB keyboard to decrypt the root parition. However, I desperately want to abandon this workaround.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yuankun.me/img/keyboard-not-found-press-any-key.png" alt="Keyboard not found, press any key to continue&amp;hellip;">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Home Server</title><link>https://yuankun.me/posts/home-server-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 20:50:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuankun.me/posts/home-server-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I came into possession of an old computer. Instead of letting it gather dust in the corner, I thought it would be a good idea to repurpose it as a home server. Primarily, I wanted a Samba Server, but I may go further to run other self-hosted services like NextCloud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through my home server setup process.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>