<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>arch on yuankun@net $</title><link>https://yuankun.me/tags/arch/</link><description>Recent content in arch on yuankun@net $</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 20:50:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuankun.me/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup a Development Machine</title><link>https://yuankun.me/posts/dev-machine-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 20:50:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuankun.me/posts/dev-machine-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few days ago, I did a &lt;a href="https://yuankun.me/posts/home-server-setup" >home server build&lt;/a>. Today I want to have a clean OS reinstallation on my development machine, because of a few things:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The root partition on this machine is almost full (thank you, my two years ago self).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I got a lot of &lt;code>__common_interrupt: 1.55 No irq handler for vector&lt;/code> errors during the system bootup. There&amp;rsquo;s a thread in the Arch Forum discussing this issue. I tried booting up the system with several different combinations of kernel parameters mentioned in the thread, but none helped. It seems like the only working solution is to upgrade the BIOS firmware.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I cannot decrypt the root partition without using my bluetooth keyboard, in the meantime I cannot use my bluetooth keyboard before the root partition is decrypted and mounted (because the bluetooth service sits in the root partition). This is a chicken-egg problem. My current hack around is to use a wired USB keyboard to decrypt the root parition. But I desperately want to eliminate the use of this USB keyboard.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://yuankun.me/img/keyboard-not-found-press-any-key.png" alt="Keyboard not found, press any key to continue&amp;amp;hellip;">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up a Home Server</title><link>https://yuankun.me/posts/home-server-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 20:50:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuankun.me/posts/home-server-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I came into possession of an old computer. Instead of letting it gather dust in the corner, I thought it would be a good idea to repurpose it as a home server. Primarily, I wanted a Samba Server, but I may go further to run other self-hosted services like NextCloud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through my home server setup process.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>