<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gcp on Yuankun&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://yuankun.me/tags/gcp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gcp on Yuankun&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:47:03 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yuankun.me/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Terraform Module to List Google Cloud Service Agents</title>
      <link>https://yuankun.me/posts/a-terraform-module-to-list-google-cloud-service-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:47:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuankun.me/posts/a-terraform-module-to-list-google-cloud-service-agents/</guid>
      <description>There are two types of service accounts in Google Cloud: user-managed service accounts, which are used by user applications to talk to Google Cloud; and Google-managed services accounts, which are used by Google Cloud internally. Among the second category, there is a special subtype of service accounts called Google Cloud Service Agents. Service Agents are used by Google Cloud services to run internal processes so that user requested operations can be fulfilled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GCP IPs All Appear in US, and It Is an Intended Behavior</title>
      <link>https://yuankun.me/posts/gcp-ips-all-appear-in-us-and-it-is-an-intended-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 23:12:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yuankun.me/posts/gcp-ips-all-appear-in-us-and-it-is-an-intended-behavior/</guid>
      <description>As you may have already known, all the IPs of Google Cloud Platform share the same geolocation, which is the US. This buggy thing has been marked as &amp;ldquo;intended behavior&amp;rdquo;, so no fix would be expected in the future. Even ironically, the guy who raised this issue was &amp;ldquo;kindly advised&amp;rdquo; to contact Google&amp;rsquo;s legal department. Here is the issue ticket.
Dear Google, when people create a network in a chosen region, they expect the public IPs of the network to be in that region.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>